<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on ryynexx</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on ryynexx</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 17:30:00 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Free from Waiting: Async Programming Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/async_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 17:30:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/async_programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-waiting-is-a-bad-idea&#34;&gt;Why Waiting Is a Bad Idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, patience can be a virtue in life, but when it comes to software, waiting is rarely a good idea. Users want applications to be fast and responsive. Long delays and endless loading loops create frustration and drive people away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind the scenes, however, many apps and websites perform time-consuming tasks such as fetching data, reading files, or communicating with servers. In synchronous programming, these tasks block everything else until they finish. That is why users often encounter the dreaded loading spinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD for Beginners: What It Is and Why It Matters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ci_cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ci_cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder how software updates roll out so frequently and efficiently?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making changes to a large codebase, ensuring it’s error-free, and deploying it to users sounds slow and tedious. Yet modern apps update daily, sometimes multiple times a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer lies in &lt;strong&gt;CI/CD — Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery/Deployment&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s fast-paced software world, writing good code is only half the story. Getting that code safely, quickly, and reliably into production is just as important. CI/CD helps developers do exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Huffman Coding Made Simple: Compressing Without Compromise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/huffman_coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/huffman_coding/</guid>
      <description>A beginner-friendly guide to Huffman Coding — how it works, how to encode and decode, and why it remains a cornerstone of data compression.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Multithreading in Python: A Beginner&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/multithreading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 17:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/multithreading/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wished you could complete all your tasks at once—handle chores, finish assignments, and relax—all simultaneously? While humans might struggle with efficient multitasking, your computer excels at it. Thanks to &lt;strong&gt;multithreading&lt;/strong&gt;, it can run multiple instructions concurrently. This is what allows your browser to load multiple tabs at once and enables a game to respond to input while rendering graphics in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide will walk you through what multithreading is, why it matters, and how to use it effectively in Python.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Command Line to Automation: Your Bash Journey Begins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bash_scripting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 17:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bash_scripting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being on your terminal, you must have faced doing a single task repetitively. For that, we have &lt;strong&gt;Bash scripting&lt;/strong&gt; — it lets you automate repetitive tasks using a single command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-bash-scripting&#34;&gt;What is Bash Scripting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bash&lt;/strong&gt; (Bourne Again Shell) is the default command-line shell on most Linux distributions and macOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Bash script&lt;/strong&gt; is a file that contains commands written line by line, which the shell can execute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s like writing a to-do list for your computer — and by running the script, all your commands in it will run on their own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effortless Transfers with rsync: A Power Tool for Every Linux User</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rsyn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 17:30:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rsyn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with files across directories or systems? &lt;code&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt; makes it faster, smarter, and easier — and it’s one of the best tools every Linux user should know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-rsync&#34;&gt;Understanding rsync&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-rsync&#34;&gt;What is rsync?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt; stands for &lt;strong&gt;remote synchronization&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s a command-line utility for efficiently transferring and synchronizing files between local or remote systems on Linux and Unix-like systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-use-rsync-over-cp-or-scp&#34;&gt;Why use rsync over cp or scp?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While &lt;code&gt;cp&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;scp&lt;/code&gt; are helpful for basic file transfers, &lt;code&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt; offers features that make it superior:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Raw Data to Insight: Your Guide to Python&#39;s Data Science Trio — Pandas, NumPy, and Matplotlib</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pyhton_libraries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pyhton_libraries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;from-raw-data-to-insight-your-guide-to-pythons-data-science-trio--pandas-numpy-and-matplotlib&#34;&gt;From Raw Data to Insight: Your Guide to Python&amp;rsquo;s Data Science Trio — Pandas, NumPy, and Matplotlib&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python has become the language of choice for data science, analytics, AI, and scientific computing. The reason for that lies in its powerful data manipulation libraries — the essential trio of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NumPy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pandas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matplotlib&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a must-use combo for dealing with raw data, numbers, calculations, and even visualization of any data. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re exploring sales trends, running scientific simulations, or building machine learning models — this is where it all begins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying the Kernel: A Journey into Compilation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kernel_compilation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 20:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kernel_compilation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered how your operating system, the very foundation of your digital world, comes to life? At its heart lies the kernel, the core program that manages your computer&amp;rsquo;s resources, from the CPU and memory to peripherals. While most users interact with their OS through a user-friendly interface, the kernel operates behind the scenes, diligently orchestrating everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how does this essential piece of software get built and tailored to your specific hardware? The answer lies in kernel compilation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Secure Connections: A Dive into SSH</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 15:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ssh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s interconnected world, secure access to remote systems is a game-changer for administrators, developers, and IT professionals. Secure Shell (SSH) stands as the ultimate tool for establishing encrypted connections to remote machines over an unsecured network. This blog will walk you through SSH’s core concepts, its working mechanism, and how to make the most of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-ssh&#34;&gt;What is SSH?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SSH, or Secure Shell, is a cryptographic network protocol designed to enable secure communication between two devices. It replaces outdated protocols like Telnet and FTP, which transmit data in plain text, leaving them vulnerable to eavesdropping and cyber threats. With SSH, all data is encrypted, ensuring both privacy and security during transmission.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Launch Your Site Swiftly: Harnessing Hugo for Rapid Web Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugo_site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 09:30:09 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hugo_site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you seeking a streamlined alternative to traditional web content management? Dive into Hugo, a powerhouse static site generator (SSG) renowned for its exceptional speed and efficiency. Ideal for developers, writers, and entrepreneurs alike, Hugo simplifies the creation and upkeep of high-performance websites. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore Hugo&amp;rsquo;s core strengths, guide you through setting up your project, and walk through deploying it on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-opt-for-hugo&#34;&gt;Why Opt for Hugo?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo&amp;rsquo;s popularity stems from its robust features:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hack Your Productivity with Git &amp; GitHub: A Must-Read Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/git_github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 09:43:45 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/git_github/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world of coding, keeping track of changes, collaborating with fellow developers, and ensuring that you never lose progress is crucial. That&amp;rsquo;s where &lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt; come in! Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner or an experienced coder, mastering these tools can &lt;strong&gt;streamline your workflow&lt;/strong&gt; and make software development a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog, we’ll dive deep into &lt;strong&gt;what Git and GitHub are, why they’re important, and how to get started&lt;/strong&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore the power of version control!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 09:43:45 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;my first post&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
