<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Development on ryynexx</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/software-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Development on ryynexx</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 17:30:00 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/software-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Free from Waiting: Async Programming Explained</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/async_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 17:30:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/async_programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-waiting-is-a-bad-idea&#34;&gt;Why Waiting Is a Bad Idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, patience can be a virtue in life, but when it comes to software, waiting is rarely a good idea. Users want applications to be fast and responsive. Long delays and endless loading loops create frustration and drive people away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind the scenes, however, many apps and websites perform time-consuming tasks such as fetching data, reading files, or communicating with servers. In synchronous programming, these tasks block everything else until they finish. That is why users often encounter the dreaded loading spinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CI/CD for Beginners: What It Is and Why It Matters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ci_cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ci_cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder how software updates roll out so frequently and efficiently?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making changes to a large codebase, ensuring it’s error-free, and deploying it to users sounds slow and tedious. Yet modern apps update daily, sometimes multiple times a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer lies in &lt;strong&gt;CI/CD — Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery/Deployment&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today’s fast-paced software world, writing good code is only half the story. Getting that code safely, quickly, and reliably into production is just as important. CI/CD helps developers do exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
